# Rishabh Kharbanda

## Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer

Kitchener, ON Canada | P: +1 548-333-7750 | <u>kharbanda.rishabh7@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/rishabh-kharbanda/</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a keen learner, Graduated from Conestoga College in Aug 2020, I've completed my Post Graduation in Web Design and Development actively looking for opportunities. Previously I've completed my Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Sciences and professionally worked as a Software Engineer for 2 years.

Portfolio Link: https://rishabhkharbanda.netlify.app/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Kitchener Autobody Inc. – Kitchener, ON Canada

Business Manager [Part-Time], Business Development & Operations

May 2019 – Present

• Managed cross-functional team and collaborated with business development, finance accounts, office management and car rental business management.

Goldman Sachs – Bengaluru, India
Software Engineer[Consultant], Regulatory Operations Trade Reporting

Sept 2017 – Apr 2019

## Java Developer, Trade Reporting Gateway

- Leading a team of 5 for Regulatory Trade Reporting, my responsibilities included developing medium to large scale java development projects focused on delivering the best experience for the application Trade Reporting Gateway with robust delivery of code into the production environment with zero tolerance for post-implementation issues.
- Invested time in resolving L3 escalations on tight SLAs, project scoping, planning and helping out to write detailed level technical and functional documentation which helps mentor junior engineers.

### Automation & DevOps Engineer, Regulatory Operations

- Developing automation tools using shell scripting and Java to reduce L1/L2 effort.
- Reviewing major code changes and taking care of build and deploy across regulatory applications for various environments.

Infosys Limited – Bengaluru, India Systems Engineer

Aug 2017 - Apr 2019

• Mapped as a Software Engineer to Goldman Sachs at client offices.

## COVID-19 Dashboard — React/D3.js Web Application

Frontend Project using Public API

- COVID-19 Dashboard built in React and D3.js using a public API.
- The project features a race chart, historical data and geographical representations.
- Technologies Used
  - o React.js, D3.js as frontend javascript technologies.
  - o SASS with CSS Grid and Flexbox for styling.
  - o Github, Github Pages, Firebase Hosting for Deployment.
- URL: <a href="https://coronavirus-dash.web.app">https://coronavirus-dash.web.app</a>

## **The Job Hunt** — Angular/Firebase Web Application

**Full Stack Project** 

- The Job Hunt is a platform which collects data from various Job Search platforms such as Linkedin Jobs, Indeed, Glassdoor etc, perform vigorous algorithms to filter out the best opportunities and collate them together for young professionals of Canada looking to thrive in the field of technology.
- Technologies Used
  - o Angular 9 as frontend technology.
  - o Algolia for front end search
  - o Github, Github Pages, Firebase Hosting for Deployment.
  - o Node, Cheerios for web scraping, data modeling and backend services.
  - o CRON, Heroku for Node worker automation and deployment.
- URL: <a href="https://thejobhunt.web.app">https://thejobhunt.web.app</a>

## **Squeeze Now** — Vue/MongoDB Web Application + API

Serverless Cloud Functions Project

- Squeeze now is a utility which helps shorten URLs to a smaller length with duplicate checks, custom or auto-generated slugs available.
- The project uses Vercel Serverless Node Cloud Functions to operate and a static Vue.js application to handle API requests for the frontend.
- The project also hosts an API with public access for anyone to use or build upon a front-end application.
- URL Shorteners in general help reduce URL length and can also be a good resource to memorise small domain shortcuts.
- Technologies Used
  - o Vue.js as frontend technology.
  - o Github, Vercel, Vercel Cloud Functions for Deployment.
  - o Node serverless functions for backend services.
  - o MongoDB, Monk, Yup used for NoSQL database and schema validations.
- URL: https://squeeze.now.sh

#### **EDUCATION**

Conestoga College – Kitchener, ON Canada Web Design & Development, Ontario College Graduate Certificate 3.8/4.0 *May* 2019 – *Aug* 2020

Chitkara University – Baddi, HP India Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Sciences 7.2/9.0 *Aug* 2013 – *Aug* 2017

#### **ADDITIONAL**

#### **Technical Skills:**

- Core Java, J2EE, Hibernate, Spring, restAPI, Data Structures and Algorithms, Oracle, DB2, Sybase IQ, MySQL, Unix CLI, Bash, shell scripting, host management
- Angular.js, React.js, React Hooks, Vue.js, JQuery, Vanilla Javascript, ES6, D3.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Firebase, Web Scraping, Cheerio.js, Puppeteer.js, Vercel, Heroku, Github Pages, Google Cloud Hosting, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Bulma, SCSS
- Python and Django Framework [self experienced]

Technical Languages: Java, Javascript, Python

Skills: Keen Learner, Strong Analytical Thinking, Team Management, Detail Oriented, Self Motivated